One of the greatest ways that this country has managed to make black people no longer the fighters that we were born to be is by convincing us that we are free enough.
Y'all can go to college. You're free enough.
People can get nice cars and nice houses and, you know, be considered rich.
So you're free enough.
Yeah, only certain black people are oppressed.
The rest of y'all, you know, if you can figure out how to pull yourself up by your bootstraps, then you're good.
So, like, what's the problem? You're free enough.
You're free enough. When we ask for more, we're told, why do you need more?
When we ask to be remembered for what we haven't been given, we are told, why are you still talking about that?
When we are told, well, you have, so why do you care about this other person not having?
Not enough of us think about community to understand that if all of us aren't free, then none of us really are.
When I say free, what I mean is free to be able to access the pursuit of happiness in the same way as the counterparts who have kept us from that from the beginning.
Thank you.